<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Alex Haslam</title>
    <link>https://alxhslm.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Alex Haslam</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 21:28:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alxhslm.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hand Writing Generation</title>
      <link>https://alxhslm.github.io/projects/hand-writing-generation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 21:28:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alxhslm.github.io/projects/hand-writing-generation/</guid>
      <description>This was a more advanced project to gain more practical experience with deep learning with unstructured data. With all of the recent hype around generative AI, also thought it would be interesting to use some form of generative model.
Objective The aim of this project is to:
Train a model to classify hand-written alphanumeric characters Generate synthetic hand-written characters using the same model I decided to use a Variational autoencoder since it is one of the few widely used models uniting deep learning and Bayesian methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coffee Rating Prediction</title>
      <link>https://alxhslm.github.io/projects/coffee-rating-prediction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 20:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alxhslm.github.io/projects/coffee-rating-prediction/</guid>
      <description>This was my first personal ML project. The goal was to familiarise myself with XGBoost and AWS Lambda. I enjoy drinking nice coffee, so I chose a topic which I hoped would help me buy better coffee in the future &amp;#x2615;.
Objective The objective of this project is to be able to predict how highly rated a coffee would be on CoffeeReview.com based purely on information about the coffee such as:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://alxhslm.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alxhslm.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I’m an engineer based in London, with expertise in modelling, simulation and machine learning. I enjoy quickly mastering new skills to solve challenging problems.
Experience Optimal Agriculture Senior Engineer London UK - Sept 2020 to Present Deploying fully autonomous greenhouses using state-of-the-art control algorithms McLaren Racing Simulation Engineer Woking UK - Aug 2012 to Nov 2016 Developing models of components, simulator control algorithms and lap-time simulations Education PhD Engineering Imperial College London - Nov 2016 to Sept 2020 Investigating transmission of vibrations through bearings in rotating machines, using modelling and advanced simulation techniques.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
